Guide to the Gwyn B. Price Papers, 1924-1972
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Gwyn B. Price papers 1924-1972
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Price, Gwyn Brantley.
18.0 Linear Feet Approximately 13,726 Items
Long-time employee of the North Carolina Rural Electrification Authority and resident of Raleigh, N.C.
Chiefly clippings on rural electrification amassed by Price during his long employment with the North Carolina Rural Electrification Authority. Also includes correspondence; a typescript of The Story of a Mountain Missionary, Rev. James Floyd Fletcher, 1858-1946 by A. J. Fletcher of Raleigh; and a mimeographed copy of Rural Electrification in North Carolina by Joseph Deutsch (Chapel Hill, 1944).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Gwyn B. Price Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1973.
Collection Overview
Chiefly clippings on rural electrification amassed by Gwyn B. Price during his long employment with the North Carolina Rural Electrification Authority. Also includes correspondence; a typescript of The Story of a Mountain Missionary, Rev. James Floyd Fletcher, 1858-1946 by A. J. Fletcher of Raleigh; and a mimeographed copy of Rural Electrification in North Carolina by Joseph Deutsch (Chapel Hill, 1944).
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Price, Gwyn B.
Fletcher, James Floyd, Reverend
North Carolina. Rural Electrification Authority
Rural electrification -- North Carolina
Missionaries -- North Carolina
Electric utilities -- North Carolina
North Carolina -- History
Burke County (N.C.)
Caldwell County (N.C.)
Wake County (N.C.)
Contents of Collection
- Alphabetical Papers Series, 1935-1972, (11 boxes)
  - A-Br (Box 1)
  - Bu-Cal (Box 2)
  - Cam-D (Box 3)
  - E (Box 4)
  - F-G (Box 5)
  - H-J (Box 6)
  - K-N (Box 7)
  - O-Ran (Box 8)
  - Rat-Ru (Box 9)
  - S-V (Box 10)
  - W-Y (Box 11)
- Chronological Papers Series, 1924-1969, (6 boxes)
  - 1924-1948 (Box 12)
  - 1949-1953 (Box 13)
  - 1954-1959 (Box 14)
  - 1960-1962 (Box 15)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 16)
  - 1964-1969 (Box 17)